Sunil Suckoo

(734) 255-5138 sunilsuckoo.github.io ssuckoo16@amherst.edu

Profile

- Experienced social researcher, specializing on American millennials.
- Proven track record of implementing effective institutional change.
- Interests: random acts of kindness, independent films, modern art.

Skills

Ethnography Field Studies

Diary Studies Interviewing

Survey Design Card Sorting

Focus Groups Presentation

Awards/Honors

Donald S. Pitkin Prize......2016 \$400 to best Anthropology-Sociology thesis out of 12 honors theses.

Watson Fellowship Finalist....2016 6% admit rate, 4 students selected on strength of research proposal, personal statement, and interview.

Valedictorian......2012
Rank 1 out of 200+ students.

Wilfred D. Webb Award.......2012 The valedictorian with the strongest commitment to community service.

Mathematics Award......2012 \$25 to most promising AP Calculus student out of 20 students.

English/Writing Award...........2012 \$25 to AP English student with the best writing skills out of 25 students.

Education

Amherst College (3.74 GPA) Graduated May 2016

B.A. in Anthropology, Magna Cum Laude Latin Honors

Danish Institute for Study AbroadCopenhagen, Denmark
August 2014—May 2015

• Produced 10-page policy proposal for the Danish government based on my own field studies, interviews, and diary studies.

Work Experience

Gregory S. Call Research Fellow

June-August 2015

Amherst College

• Wrote concise (1-3 pages) and in-depth (10-15 pages) thesis proposals, granting me faculty support/full funding (\$1500+).

Mellon Initiative Research Fellow

June-August 2014

University of Chicago

- Conducted qualitative research (ethnography, field studies, interviews, card sorting) on diversity in higher education.
- Presented at the Leadership Alliance National Symposium (350+ undergraduates, 50 grad students, 25 doctoral scholars) and UChicago Research Symposium (20+ scholars).

Resident Counselor (RC)

August 2014—May 2016

Amherst College Office of Student Affairs

- Designed and issued 10+ surveys with 100% response rate.
- Planned 20+ events with nearly perfect attendance (20-25 students) using my survey data and ethnographic insights.
- Co-founded the RC Council, which successfully advocated for a 30% increase in salary and 150% increase in yearly budget.

Research Assistant

October 2013—May 2014

Amherst College Residential Life Department

 Recruited 10+ staff/administrators at similar institutions (Williams, Middlebury, etc.) for interviews to evaluate policies.

Research Projects

Millennial Cyborgs (Senior Thesis) August 2015—May 2016

- Wrote 110-page thesis on American millennials' relationship to technology based on 5+ years of ethnographic, field studies, diary studies, and interviewing, and 140+ surveys.
- Received praise from 50+ students, 20+ doctoral scholars, and 10+ business professionals at the Five College Anthropology Conference for my clarity and potential for improving the technology-rich lives of millennials.

Diversity at Amherst College

June-August 2014

 Met with Amherst College President several times and successfully advocated for 10 new paid staff positions at the resource centers based on my research at UChicago.